# JAEMIN YOO

Postdoctoral Research Fellow @ Carnegie Mellon University **Email:** jaeminyoo@cmu.edu **\pi Web:** jaeminyoo.github.io

#### **BIOGRAPHY**

I am a postdoctoral research fellow in the Heinz College of Information Systems and Public Policy at Carnegie Mellon University. I received my Ph.D. and B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering from Seoul National University. My research areas include data mining and machine learning on graphs, multivariate time series forecasting, and interpretable machine learning. I have published more than 10 first-author papers in major data mining and machine learning venues including KDD, WSDM, TheWebConf, and NeurIPS. I am a recipient of the Google PhD Fellowship, Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship, and the Outstanding Dissertation Award from Seoul National University.

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Heinz College of Information Systems and Advisor: <i>Prof. Leman Akoglu</i>	Mar. 2022 - Present Public Policy
EDUCATION	
Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering Advisor: Prof. U Kang Thesis: Probabilistic Approaches for Node and Graph Classification	Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2022
Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering	Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2016
AWARDS & HONORS	
S-Oil Outstanding Dissertation Award	
SNU CSE Outstanding Dissertation Award	
One of the Best-Ranked Papers of ICDM 2021	
SNU BK21 Outstanding Graduate Student Award	Jul. 2021
SIAM Student Travel Award (SDM 2021)	Apr. 2021
SNU BK21 Star Researcher Award	Feb. 2021
Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship	Dec. 2020
Yulchon AI Star Award	Sep. 2020
Google PhD Fellowship (Machine Learning)	Sep. 2019
Samsung HumanTech Paper Award (Honorable Mention)	Feb. 2019
Google Conference Scholarship (ICDM 2017)	Nov. 2017

#### **PREPRINTS**

- [i3] UltraProp: Principled and Explainable Propagation on Large Graphs Meng-Chieh Lee, Shubhranshu Shekhar, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and Christos Faloutsos arXiv Preprint (2023)
- [i2] SlenderGNN: Accurate, Robust, and Interpretable GNN, and the Reasons for its Success <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>\*, Meng-Chieh Lee\*, Shubhranshu Shekhar, and Christos Faloutsos **arXiv Preprint** (2022; \*equal contribution)
- [i1] Self-supervision is not magic: Understanding Data Augmentation in Image Anomaly Detection <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Tiancheng Zhao, and Leman Akoglu **arXiv Preprint** (2022)

#### **TUTORIALS**

- [t2] Mining of Real-world Hypergraphs: Concepts, Patterns, and Generators Geon Lee, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and Kijung Shin <u>TheWebConf 2023</u>
- [t1] Mining of Real-world Hypergraphs: Concepts, Patterns, and Generators Geon Lee, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and Kijung Shin ICDM 2022 and CIKM 2022

#### CONFERENCES

- [c16] Accurate Stock Movement Prediction with Self-supervised Learning from Sparse Noisy Tweets Yejun Soun\*, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>\*, Minyong Cho, Jihyeong Jeon, and U Kang **BigData 2022** (acceptance rate 122/633 = 19.2%; \*equal contribution)
- [c15] Reciprocity in Directed Hypergraphs: Measures, Findings, and Generators Sunwoo Kim, Minyoung Choe, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and Kijung Shin ICDM 2022 (acceptance rate 174/890 = 19.6%)
- [c14] Accurate Node Feature Estimation with Structured Variational Graph Autoencoder <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Hyunsik Jeon, Jinhong Jung, and U Kang KDD 2022 (acceptance rate 254/1695 = 15.0%)
- [c13] Model-Agnostic Augmentation for Accurate Graph Classification <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Sooyeon Shim, and U Kang **TheWebConf 2022** (acceptance rate 323/1822 = 17.7%)
- [c12] MiDaS: Representative Sampling from Real-world Hypergraphs
  Minyoung Choe, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Geon Lee, Woonsung Baek, U Kang, and Kijung Shin **TheWebConf 2022** (acceptance rate 323/1822 = 17.7%)
- [c11] Transition Matrix Representation of Trees with Transposed Convolutions
   <u>Jaemin Yoo</u> and Lee Sael
   SDM 2022 (acceptance rate 83/298 = 27.8%)
- [c10] Accurate Graph-Based PU Learning without Class Prior Jaemin Yoo\*, Junghun Kim\*, Hoyoung Yoon\*, Geonsoo Kim, Changwon Jang, and U Kang ICDM 2021 (regular paper; top 98/990 = 9.9%; \*equal contribution) Selected as one of the best-ranked papers of ICDM 2021 for fast-track journal invitation

[c9] Accurate Multivariate Stock Movement Prediction via Data-Axis Transformer with Multi-Level Contexts

Jaemin Yoo, Yejun Soun, Yong-chan Park, and U Kang

**KDD 2021** (acceptance rate 238/1541 = 15.4%)

[c8] Gaussian Soft Decision Trees for Interpretable Feature-Based Classification <u>Jaemin Yoo</u> and Lee Sael

**PAKDD 2021** (acceptance rate 157/768 = 20.4%)

[c7] Attention-Based Autoregression for Accurate and Efficient Multivariate Time Series Forecasting <u>Jaemin Yoo</u> and U Kang

**SDM 2021** (acceptance rate 85/400 = 21.3%)

- [c6] Sampling Subgraphs with Guaranteed Treewidth for Accurate and Efficient Graphical Inference Jaemin Yoo, U Kang, Mauro Scanagatta, Giorgio Corani, and Marco Zaffalon WSDM 2020 (acceptance rate 91/615 = 14.8%)
- [c5] Knowledge Extraction with No Observable Data <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Minyong Cho, Taebum Kim, and U Kang **NeurIPS 2019** (acceptance rate 1428/6743 = 21.2%)
- [c4] EDiT: Interpreting Ensemble Models via Compact Soft Decision Trees
   Jaemin Yoo and Lee Sael
   ICDM 2019 (acceptance rate 194/1046 = 18.5%)
- [c3] Belief Propagation Network for Hard Inductive Semi-Supervised Learning <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Hyunsik Jeon, and U Kang **IJCAI 2019** (acceptance rate 850/4752 = 17.9%)
- [c2] Fast and Scalable Distributed Loopy Belief Propagation on Real-World Graphs Saehan Jo, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and U Kang WSDM 2018 (acceptance rate 83/514 = 16.3%)
- [c1] Supervised Belief Propagation: Scalable Supervised Inference on Attributed Networks <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Saehan Jo, and U Kang ICDM 2017 (regular paper; top 72/778 = 9.3%)

#### **JOURNALS**

- [j3] Graph-based PU Learning for Binary and Multiclass Classification without Class Prior <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>\*, Junghun Kim\*, Hoyoung Yoon\*, Geonsoo Kim, Changwon Jang, and U Kang **Knowledge and Information Systems** (SCIE Journal, 2022; \*equal contribution)
- [j2] Signed Random Walk Diffusion for Effective Representation Learning in Signed Graphs Jinhong Jung, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and U Kang PLOS ONE (SCIE Journal, 2022)
- [j1] Efficient Learning of Bounded-Treewidth Bayesian Networks from Complete and Incomplete Data Sets

Mauro Scanagatta, Giorgio Corani, Marco Zaffalon, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and U Kang International Journal of Approximate Reasoning (SCIE Journal, 2018)

## INVITED TALKS

SNU AI Summer School 2022, Online	Aug. 2022
SK C&C, Online	Aug. 2022
KAIST School of Computing, Online	Jul. 2022
AWS Deep Learning Group, Online	Jul. 2022
EIRIC Seminar, Online	Apr. 2022
KAIST School of Electrical Engineering, Daejeon, South Korea	Feb. 2022
LG AI Research Tech Talk, Seoul, South Korea	Feb. 2022
KAIST AI Student Colloquium, Online	Oct. 2021
SNU AI Summer School 2021, Online	Aug. 2021
SNU AI Institute (AIIS) Retreat 2021, Seoul, South Korea	Apr. 2021
NAVER Online Tech Talk, Online	Dec. 2020
SNU AI Summer School 2020, Seoul, South Korea	Aug. 2020
SNU Hospital, Seoul, South Korea	Jul. 2020
SNU AI Institute (AIIS) Retreat 2020, Seoul, South Korea	Jun. 2020
Kakao Enterprise, Seongnam, South Korea	Jan. 2020
Korea Software Congress (KSC) 2019, Pyeongchang, South Korea	Dec. 2019
SNU Center for AI (SCAI) Retreat 2019, Chuncheon	Jul. 2019
Samsung Electronics, Suwon, South Korea	Mar. 2019
IDSIA, Lugano, Switzerland	Jul. 2018
Korea Software Congress 2017, Busan, South Korea	Dec. 2017
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Teaching Asssistant	
• TA @ Mathematics for Machine Learning, LG Chem	Dec. 2021 - Jan. 2022
• TA @ Hyundai AI Master, Hyundai Motors	Aug. 2021 - Oct. 2022
• TA @ Samsung DS <sup>2</sup> (Deep Learning), Samsung Electronics	Apr. 2018 - Feb. 2019
• TA @ Deep Learning, SNU Fourth Industrial Revolution Academ	y Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2018
• TA @ Distributed Computing, SNU Big Data Academy	Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2017
• TA @ Distributed Computing, SNU Big Camp	Aug. 2016 - Feb. 2017
• TA @ Large Data Analysis (M1522.000900_002), SNU	Fall 2017
• TA @ Introduction to Data Mining (M1522.001400_001), SNU .	Spring 2017
- TA @ Data Structures (M1522.001600_002), SNU $\ \cdot\ \cdot\ \cdot\ \cdot$ .	Fall 2016
Mentoring/Tutoring	
• Student Mentor @ Undergraduate Research Program, SNU	Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020
• Project Mentor @ DL-based Demand Forecasting, LG Electronics	
- I I Jood Monday & DE Sassa Domaila I Officialing, Ed Diccironics	Mar. 2020 - May 2020
	_
• Writing Tutor @ Writing in Scientific and Technology (031.004_{0}	002, 020}), SNU Fall 2015
	002, 020}), SNU Fall 2015 88), SNU Spring 2015

#### RESEARCH PROJECTS

(SW Star Lab) Flexible and Efficient Compression of Neural Networks Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2022
Malicious User Detection with Relational Information (w/ NCSOFT) Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021
Personalized Recommendation of Items in E-commerce (w/ Wemakeprice) . Mar. 2019 - Dec. 2019
Content Recommendation based on Watch History (w/ SK Telecom) Mar. 2018 - Nov. 2018
Research on Statistical Learning and Inference with PGMs (w/ IDSIA) $Mar.\ 2016$ - $Oct.\ 2018$
Temporal Stock Price Prediction (w/ eMoney)
Development of Distributed ML Library for Industry (w/ SK Telecom) Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2016

#### **PATENTS**

#### Registered

- <u>Jaemin Yoo</u> and U Kang, "Apparatus and Method for Classifying Nodes", KR-Registration No. 10-1924832 (2018)
- Taebum Kim, <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, and U Kang, "Method for Compressing Deep Learning Neural Networks and Apparatus for Performing the Same", KR-Registration No. 10-2199285 (2020)
- <u>Jaemin Yoo</u> and U Kang, "Method for Extracting Knowledge from Artificial Neural Network and Apparatus for Performing the Same", KR-Registration No. 10-2345262 (2021)

#### Filed

- <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Sooyeon Shim, and U Kang, "Apparatus and Method for Data Augmentation", KR-Application No. 10-2021-0169909 (2021)
- <u>Jaemin Yoo</u>, Hyunsik Jeon, Jinhong Jung, and U Kang, "Apparatus and Method for Predicting Feature of Node", KR-Application No. 10-2021-0172385 (2021)

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Session Chair
$\bullet$ KDD (ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining) $$ 2022
Program Committee Member
<ul> <li>KDD (ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining)</li></ul>
Conference Reviewer
<ul> <li>ICLR (The International Conference on Learning Representations)</li></ul>
Journal Reviewer
<ul> <li>Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery</li></ul>

### External Conference Reviewer

$\bullet$ ICLR (The International Conference on Learning Representations) $$
$\bullet$ NeurIPS (Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems)
$\bullet$ The WebConf (The Web Conference)
$\bullet$ KDD (ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining) $$ $$ 2018 - 2020
$\bullet$ BigComp (IEEE International Conference on Big Data and Smart Computing) $$ $2017$ - $2020$
$\bullet$ CIKM (ACM Intl. Conference on Information and Knowledge Management) $$ 2017 - 2019
$\bullet$ WSDM (ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining)
$\bullet$ ICDM (IEEE International Conference on Data Mining) $\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\ .\$
• SAC (ACM/SIGAPP Symposium on Applied Computing)